Finding Aid for the Photographers' Collection LSC.0098
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Shelflist
  - ***Photographers Collection., 43 photographs.
    - "Wo-Men Working Series", 11 items.
      - "Auto Mechanic, Wo-Men Working", ca. 1978; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      - "Wo-Men Working Series, Department of Sanitation", ca. 1978; Image: 35 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 40 cm. Signed in pencil on mat. (Box 2)
      - "Wo-men Working, Housepainter", ca. 1981; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      - "Wo-Men Working, Denise", ca. 1978; Image: 28 x 34 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. Signed in pencil on mount. (Box 2)
      - "Woman Laborers Series, Mechanic", ca. 1978; Image: 27 x 26 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      - "Gas Company, Wo-Men Working", ca. 1979; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      - "Drill Press, Los Angeles. Welder, Wo-Men Working", ca. 1978; Image: 35 x 37 cm.; Mounted: 50 x 41 cm. Signed in pencil on mat. (Box 2)
      - "Wo-men Working, Welder", ca. 1978; Image: 36 x 27 cm.; Mounted: 50 x 40 cm. Signed in pencil on mat. (Box 2)
      - "Wo-Men Working Series, L.A. Dept. of Parks", ca. 1978; Image: 36 x 38 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. Signed in pencil on mat. (Box 2)
    - "Brooke Whiting, photographe[d] March 24, 1983 at the Booksellers lunch to honor him on the occasion of his retirement", ca. 1983; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Jake Zeitlin, photographed at home", ca. 1979; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Robert Nathan at 90", ca. 1983; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Victory, by William Zorach, Franklin D. Murphy sculpture garden/UCLA", ca. 1984; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 36 x 24 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Maja, by Gerhard Marcks, Francklin D. Murphy sculpture garden/UCLA", ca. 1984; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 36 x 24 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "On the occasion of Ward Ritchie's 80th birthday", ca. 1985; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 19 x 25 cm.; Mounted: 26 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      Portrait of Jake Zeitlin, Ward Ritchie, and Lawrence Clark Powell taken at the home of Dr. Charles Monell.
    - "On the occasion of Ward Ritchie's 80th Birthday", ca. 1985; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 20 x 25 cm.; Mounted: 26 x 46 cm. (Box 2)
      Portrait of Jack Smith, his wife Denise, and Jake Zeitlin taken at the home of Dr. Charles Monell.
    - "Jake Zeitlin & Shakespeare firt folio", ca. 1985; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 2)
      Portrait of the booksletter inside his shop at 815 N. La Cienega Blvd., September 23, 1985.
    - "Four UCLA Librarians at Ward Ritchie 75th Birthday", ca. 1980; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 2)
      Portrait of Russell Shank, Lawrence Clark Powell, Robert Vosper, and Page Ackerman taken at the Clark Library.
    - "Isumu Noguchi", ca. 1983; Image: 35 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 50 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      "This portrait of Noguchi was a commission from Atlantic Richfield. It was made at the time of the completion of his culpture and plaza in downtown Los Angeles."
    - "Westwood", ca. 1986; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 33 x 22 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
      Portrait of a derelict sleeping on a Westwood bus-stop bench underneath a movie marquee advertising, "Down and Out in Beverly Hills."
    - "Charles Champlin, Arts Editor Los Angeles Times", ca. 1986; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 25 x 17 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Portrait of Mother with Child at her Hip by Francisco Zuniga, photographed in the Franklin D. Murphy Sculpture Garden, UCLA.", ca. 1986; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 36 x 24 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Portrait of sculpture Ptolemy III by Jean Arp, photographed in the Franklin D. Murphy sculpture garden at UCLA (with children climbing in it)", ca. 1986; Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 36 x 22 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 2)
    - "Lou Stoumen at UCLA", ca. 1977; Image: 25 x 17 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 46 x 36 cm. (Box 2)
      Portrait taken in the Franklin D. Murphy Sculpture Garden.
    - Portrait of UCLA Math professor Mark Green reading with his son, Joseph, ca. 1986; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 2)
      This photograph was presented to UCLA Library by Jake and Josephine Zeitlin in honor of Hilda Bohem on the occasion of her retirement from the Department of Special Collections--August 8, 1986.
    - "Timothy Steele", ca. 1986; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 51 x 41 cm. Title on verso of mat: "Tim Steele" (Box 2)
      Full-face portrait of the Los Angeles poet and former president of The Friends of the UCLA Library.
    - "Jake Zeitlin at 84 with 1932 portrait by Edward Weston", ca. 1986; Image: 25 x 17 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 2)
      Ektacolor portrait of the seated bookseller holding a photograph of himself at 30.
    - "Lot's wife, by Anna Mahler. Franklin D. Murphy Sculpture Garden", ca. 1984(?); Image: 12 x 9 cm.; 2 copies. (Othertype Vertical File)
      Type R print mounted in New Year's greeting card, holograph caption: "Don't look back--Ahead is a beautiful New Year! Best wishes, Marilyn."
    - Robert Nathan greeting John Weaver. Beverly Hills, California., ca. 1983; Non-archival print. Image: 21 x 25 cm. (Othertype Vertical File)
    - Dr. Franklin Murphy conducting a tour of the UCLA Franklin D. Murphy Sculpture Garden for the visiting International Association of Bibliophiles, 1985 October 3; Image: 25 x 20 cm.
  - Theatrical photographs. New York., ca. 1870-1896.; 241 items. 16.5 x 10.6 cm. Mounted photographs.
    238 items - box 110.
    3 items - box 89.
    A collection of cabinet photographs, mostly of theatrical personalities. In addition to the list below, there are several unidentified portraits.
    Sarony was the most popular photographer of his day in America and this collection reflects the fact that theatrical personalities constituted a large part of his clientelle.
    Most of the photographs in this collection are cabinet size, 16.5 x 10.6 cm. mounted. There are a few carte-de-visite portraits measuring 6.2 x 10.3 cm. Some of these duplicate the larger images.
    - Adams, Maude.
    - Alexander, Sir George., 2 items.
    - Anderson, Mary., 8 items.
    - Bangs, Frank C.
    - Barrett, Lawrence.
    - Barrett, Wilson.
    - Bean, Fannie.
    - Bell, Digby Valentine.
    - Bell, Ida.
    - Bellew, H. Kyrle., 3 items.
    - Bernhardt, Sarah., 5 items. (One mounted with program for Cleopatra)
    - Blanchard, Kitty., 2 items.
    - Booth, Edwin.
    - Brandon, Olga.
    - Brignoli, Pietro.
    - Bruno, Helen.
    - Burke, Billie.
    - Burroughs, Marie., 2 items.
    - Carew, May.
    - Carter, Mrs. Leslie., 3 items.
    - Cayvan, Georgia.
    - Chester, Leslie.
    - Claxton, Kate., 2 items.
    - Clayton, Estelle., 2 items.
    - Cleveland, Stephen Grover.
    - Coghland, Rose., 2 items.
    - Coquelin, Benoît-Constant.
    - Corlette, Ethel.
    - Crabtree, Charlotte (Lotta)., 3 items.
    - Croly, Vida.
    - Dalzelle.
    - Davenport, E. L., 2 items.
    - Davenport, Fanny., 10 items.
    - Dietz, Linda.
    - Dillon, Louise.
    - Dixey, Henry E., 6 items.
    - Don, Laura.
    - Drew, John.
    - Dyas, Ada., 2 items.
    - Fairman, James.
    - Faversham, William., 2 items.
    - Fechter, Charles Albert.
    - Fiske, Minnie Maddern.
    - Forrest, Edwin.
    - Fox, Della.
    - Fuller, Loie.
    - Gale, Minna K.
    - Gilbert, Mrs. Anne Hartley.
    - Gillett, William., (35 x 18 cm. mounted)
    - Gould, Edith Kingdon.
    - Granger, Maude.
    - Granville, Evelyn.
    - Granville, Gertie.
    - Greenwall, Marie.
    - Grey, Sibyl.
    - Grub, Lillian.
    - Hall, Pauline.
    - Heron, Bijou.
    - Hilliard, Robert C.
    - Hood, Marion.
    - Hopper, De Wolf.
    - Hopper, Edna Wallace.
    - Howson, Emma.
    - Hoyt, Caroline Miskel.
    - Irwin, May., 3 items.
    - Jefferson, Joseph., 2 items.
    - Jewett, Sarah.
    - Kelcey, Herbert.
    - Kellogg, Clara Louise., 2 items.
    - Kendal, William Hunger., 2 items.
    - Kidder, Kathryn.
    - Langtree, Lillie., 2 items.
    - Lee, Jennie.
    - LeMoyne, William.
    - Leslie, Elsie.
    - Levey, Ethel.
    - Lewis, Catherine.
    - Lewis, James., 2 items.
    - Lingard, Alice.
    - Lucca, Pauline, baroness von Wallhohen.
    - Majilton, Mrs. Marie.
    - Mannering, Mary.
    - Mantell, Robert Bruce., 2 items.
    - Marlow, Julia.
    - Martinot, Sadie., 4 items.
    - Mather, Margaret., 2 items.
    - Mehlig, Anna.
    - Millet, Maude.
    - Millward, Jessie.
    - Mitchell, Margaret Julia., 2 items.
    - Modjeska, Helena., 3 items.
    - Montague, Henry James.
    - Montague, Louisa.
    - Morris, Clara., 2 items.
    - Nast, Thomas.
    - Neilson, Adelaide., 6 items.
    - Nethersole, Olga.
    - Nillson, Christine.
    - Nordica, Lillian.
    - Opp, Julia.
    - Palmer, Minnie., 2 items.
    - Pixley, Annie.
    - Plesta, Leslie M.
    - Potter, Cora (Urquhart)., 4 items.
    - Power, Tyrone.
    - Powers, James T.
    - Prestige, Fanny.
    - Ream, Vinnie.
      A foremost American sculptress, ca. 1870-1880s.
    - Rehan, Ada., 5 items.
    - Rignold, George., 2 items.
    - Ristori, Adelaide.
    - Robe, Annie.
    - Robson, Stuart.
    - Roze, Marie.
    - Rubinstein, Anton.
    - Russell, Helen.
    - Russell, Lillian.
    - Russell, Sol Smith.
    - St. John, Mae.
    - Salvini, Alexander.
    - Sarony, Mrs.
    - Scalchi, Sofia.
    - Scott-Siddons, Mary., 4 items.
    - Seligman, Minnie.
    - Selwynn, Ethel.
    - Shirley, Madeline.
    - Sothern, Edward Hugh., 5 items.
    - Stanley, Alma.
    - Stone, Amy.
    - Studholme, Marie.
    - Summerville, Amelia.
    - Tabor, Robert Schell.
    - Tanner, Cora.
    - Tempest, Marie.
    - Templeton, Fay.
    - Thatcher, Lillian.
    - Théo, Mme.
    - Thompson, Lydia.
    - Thorne, Charles Robert, Jr.
    - Turner, Carrie., 2 items.
    - Van Osten, Ida.
    - Varian, Nina.
    - Vaughan, Kate.
    - Vaughan, Theresa.
    - Verona, Irene.
    - Vokes, Rosina., 2 items.
    - Wainright, Marie.
    - Wilson, Francis., (mounted: 30x3 x 22.2 cm.)
    - Wood, Mrs. John.
  - Photographers Collection., 8 photographs. (Box 27)
  - Fairfield. Sapphire, North Carolina., ca. 1901.; 1 item. 18 x 23.5 cm. Photograph. (Box 90)
  - *Photographers Collection., 29 items. Photographs. (Box 111)
    Florence Kemmler Schneider was a San Diego photographer and a member of the California Pictorialists. These photographs of San Diego and vicinity, ca. 1920s and 1930s, are mainly exhibit prints and of various sizes, chiefly 25.7 x 35 cm.; mounted 40.4 x 40.5 cm.
    - Spider monkeys., 2 copies, variants.
    - "Playtime.", 2 copies, variants.
    - "Childhood joys."
    - Apache.
    - "His signature."
    - Power of sunshine.
    - On a peaceful lake.
    - Supply boat.
    - Ship painters.
    - Oil drums.
    - Study on the pier.
    - Submarines.
    - Harbor study.
    - "The sea gull."
    - Painting chains., 2 copies, duplicates.
    - Unloading.
    - Rigging.
    - "Ready for the market."
    - "Evening."
    - Untitled: lumber pile.
    - "The camera enthusiast."
    - The pond.
    - San Diego de Alcala Mission.
    - The gate.
    - Untitled: factory with 7 smokestacks.
    - "The old school house."
  - *Photographers Collection., 36 items. Photographs. (Box 31)
    Roland Schneider was a San Diego photographer and a member of the California Pictorialists. These photographs of San Diego and vicinity, ca. 1920s, are mainly exhibit prints and of various sizes, chiefly 27.5 x 35 cm.; mounted 40.4 x 50.5 cm.
    - "Eucalypti."
    - Kelp.
    - Resting.
    - Broken trees.
    - The young sportsman.
    - Cleaning the beach.
    - After the day's work.
      [Removed 12/79]
    - Milk cans.
    - "Horse-Shoeing."
    - Pax Huic Domui: "Peace be to this house."
    - Metal pipes.
    - "Daylight rocket."
    - "Watersport."
    - "Circus day."
    - Unloading.
    - The tractor.
    - Summertime.
    - Untitled: children playing on the beach.
    - Untitled: plaza with statue.
    - Untitled: pier(?), Green tinted photo.
    - Untitled: bedroom furniture.
    - Untitled: surf pounding rocks.
    - Untitled: lone tree with rocks.
    - San Diego River., 2 copies, variants.
    - "Ghost trees."
    - The railing's shadow.
    - The railing.
    - "The path."
    - "Roaming o'er the sea.", 2 copies, variants.
    - "O'er the glad waves."
    - "Swelling sails."
    - Untitled: sail boat scenes., 2 different views.
    - "The dragon."
    - Mending nets.
  - Treadmill. n.p., [193-].; 1 item. 21 x 17 cm. Photograph. (Box 91)
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photographs. (Box 92)
  - John Copwer Powys. [n.p.], 1922.; 1 item. 21 x 16 cm. Photograph. (Box 93)
    Ex libris: Paul Jordan Smith.
  - James Van der Zee. New York., 1977.; 1 item. 25.4 x 20.3 cm. Photograph. (Box 94)
  - ***Photographers Collection., Photographs.
    - Prince Albert, 1945; Size/Mounted: 25 x 20 cm./40 x 35cm.; Silver print: objects superimposed over drawing of Prince Albert.
  - Buchenwald., April, 1945.; 12 photographs. Approx. 9 x 11 cm.
    Mr. Sperisen was with the U.S. Army Intelligence when he took these pictures.
  - *Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs. (Box 32)
  - Portraits. New York., 1925-1935.; 43 items. 33 x 21 cm. Tear sheets. (Box 132)
    Photographic reproductions published in Vogue and Vanity Fair of various theatrical, political, and social celebrities.
    In addition, there are 9 photos of high fashion designs by Chanel, Patou, Vionnet, etc., and several unidentified portraits.
    - Aherne, Brian
    - Arliss, George
    - Bainter, Fay
    - Baker, Phill
    - Barrett, Edith
    - Barrymore, Ethel
    - Barrymore, Lionel
    - Baruch, Bernard Mannes
    - Bennett, Joan
    - Churchill, Winston
    - Dooling, James J.
    - Doris Humphrey dancers.
    - Farley, James Aloysius
    - Farley, Morgan
    - Gable, Clark
    - Gershwin, George
    - Gordon, Ruth
    - Graham, Martha
    - Harrison, Bryon, Patton ("Pat")
    - Howard, Leslie
    - Johnson, Edward
    - Kane, Helen
    - Keeler, Ruby
    - Kreisler, Fritz
    - Kühlmann, Richard von
    - Lippmann, Walter
    - Lord, Pauline
      (see Gordon, Ruth)
    - Mann, Thomas
    - Massey, Raymond
    - Menjou, Adolphe
    - Nazimova, Alla
    - Parker, Dorothy
    - Phipps, Mrs. Ogden
    - Pitts, Za Su
    - Richberg, Donald R., (2 copies)
    - Robeson, Paul
    - Vidor, Florence
    - Wyngard, Diana
    - Claire, Ina
  - Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs. (Box 95)
  - *Photographers Collection., 82 photographs. Various large sizes. (Box 30)
    Collection of photographs, 1887-1888, mounted on cardboard: 17 views of San Francisco's Chinatown; 24 views of El Paso del Norte, Mexico [now Ciudad Juárez]; 21 views of Los Angeles, and 20 miscellaneous views, mainly of California.
  - Photographers Collection., 7 photographs.
    Photographs are of various sizes. Numbers refer to Taber's personal numbering system.
    - Sutro Heights, San Francisco, California, 1886; 4.
      View on Main Drive. (Number cropped)
    - The Seal Rocks, San Francisco, California., 4.; (Number cropped)
    - Shore view, Chinese fishing village, near Monterey., B254.
      (Probably from a Carlton E. Watkins negative)
    - Sutro Baths, Looking South. San Francisco, California., 6859.
    - General View of Lake, Golden Gate Park, San Francisco, California., 7267.
    - View of San Francisco looking East from Hopkins Art Association, showing Goat Island and Terminus S.P.R. and Oakland Ferry Boat., ca. 1895.; 7427.
    - Cliff House and Seal Rocks, from Pier, San Francisco, 1895 October 26; 7529.
    - "Mission El Carmel," Established 1770, Monterey, California., 118.
  - Photographers Collection., 24 items. Photographs. (Box 35)
    Included are a group of Hosueworth celebrities, cabinet cards, and one ovedrsize print 41 x 52.5 cm.; mounted 44.5 x 54.4 cm.
  - Photographers Collection., 18 items. Photographs. (Box 96)
  - Photographers Collection., 8 photographs. (Box 6)
  - Untitled portrait of a woman (James Van der Zee's secretary?) New York., 1926.; 1 item. 22.6 x 17.6 cm. Photograph. Mounted in a hinged mat, 50.2 x 40.5 cm., signed and dated in the plate.
  - Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs.
  - *Photographers Collection., 12 items. Photographs.
    8 items - box 97.
    - Dorothy Maynor. New York., 1939; 35 x 28 cm. Mounted and overmatted, 51 x 40.5 cm.
    - Gloria Davy as Aida. New York., 1958; 33 x 24 cm. Mounted and overmatted, 51 x 41 cm.
    - Adele Addison. New York., 1955; 32 x 24 cm. Mounted and overmatted, 51 x 41 cm.
    - Henry Miller. s.l., ca. 1940; 25 x 20 cm.
      [missing 7/81]
    - Anna May Wong, actress. s.l., ca. 1930s; 25 x 19 cm.
    - Carl Van Vechten. Self-portrait. s.l., ca. 1940s; 25 x 19 cm.
      Photograph of a portrait by Romain Brooks. s.l.
    - Carl Van Vechten. Self-portrait. s.l., 1934 March 19; 25 x 19 cm.
    - Fania Marinoff. s.l., 1917 Novwember 26; 25 x 20 cm.
    - Fania Marinoff. s.l., ca. 1925; 27 x 23 cm.
      Photograph of a portrait by Paul Thevenez.
    - Pavel Tchelitchev. s.l., 1934 November 14; 24 x 17 cm. Mounted and overmatted, 46 x 36 cm.
    - Gertrude Stein. Billignan, near Annecy, France., 1934 June 13; 16 x 24 cm. Mounted and overmatted, 41 x 51 cm.
    - [Untitled] African dancer holding spear. s.l., ca. 194-?; 18 x 13 cm.
      [A duplicate of this photograph can be found in the Arthur Todd Collection]
    - Basket I, Gertrude Stein's dog. Bellignan, near Annecy, 1934; 24 x 16 cm.
    - Gertrude Stein. Paris., 1945; 14 x 9 cm.
      Profile portrait with American flag in background; top left corner torn off.
    - Bernadine Fritz., 1934 October 15; Portrait. Hands on shoulders.
    - Hurston, Zora Neale., Portrait. 8x10.
      Copy of Van Vechten portrait of Hurston used on dustjacket of The Complete Stories by Zora Neale Hurston. New York: HarperCollins, 1995. PS 508.1 H946c 1995.
  - Photographers Collection., 2 photographs of Bernadine Fritz. (Box 97)
  - Photographers Collection. (Box 97)
    Portrait of Zora Neale Hurston. Copy of image on inside of back dustjacket of PS 508.1 H946c 1995.
  - Photographers. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 98)
    I. Santa Cruz, and Bay of Monterey ... 1863. Presentation coy fro Vischer to Mrs. [Elizabeth] Gerberding.
    II. Sunday-gatherings after mass. Ex-Mission (now Parish-Church) of San Gabriel ... 1878.
  - Photographers Collection., 8 photographs. 41 x 50 cm. Mounted 50 x 60 cm. (Box 20)
    Prints made from the original negatives in the A.C. Vroman Collection at the Los Angeles County Museum.
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photograph. (Box 101)
  - Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs. (Box 102)
  - Snapshot diary. v.p. (Calif.), ca. 1896-1945.; 2 vol. 28 cm. Photograph album and index. (Box 123, Box 124)
    About 1200 snapshots, approximately 8 x 8 cm., mounted on white bond paper in a paper binder, with a typescript commentary relating to the photographs. There is also an index to some 10,000 nitrate negatives, only a fraction of which were printed for this album.
  - Photographers Collection., 12 photographs.
  - *Portraits of Mina Cooper (Mrs. herbert A. Kelin). Carmel, Calif., 1929.; 8 items. Photographs.
    An additional 5 coy prints of a 1944 sitting by Mina Cooper Klein, 1944 are in the vertical file 98 Weston.
  - *Photographers Collection., 249 photographs. Various sizes, mounted and unmounted.
    Many of these photographs were reproduced in Westways magazine.
    Included are the following portraits: Paul Jordan Smith, Lincoln Steffans, Robinson Jeffers, John Cowper Powys, William Wilcox Robinson, Madeleine Ruthven.
    - [Isolated items] (Othertype Package 1)
      These items have been isolated from the collection because they are foxed.
      #6 E.W. Pome, 1935
      #7 Wind erosion, dunes at Oceano, 1936.
      #28 Palma Cuernavaca, 1924.
      #29 Cement workers glove, 1936.
      #52 Untitled, 1927. [Nude, mounted in green folder]
      #53 Untitled, 1934. [Crop in field]
      #54 Squash, 1932.
    - Mountain solitudes. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      #1 [Mt. Shasta]
      #2 [Potato cellar, Meyers, California]
      #3 [Cliff, Yosemite]
      #4 Meyer's Ranch, Yosemite, 1938.
      #5 Meyer's Ranch, Yosemite, 1938.
      #6 [Big Oak Flat Road, Hardin's Flat, Yosemite]
      #7 [Clyde Minaret and glacier, Yosemite]
      #8 [Granite Ridge above Lake Elzida]
      #9 [Flowers and snow]
      #10 [Foothill oaks]
      #11 Unidentified (detail[rock?])
    - Northern California., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      #1 [Glass Mountain]
      #2 [Remnants of volcanic blast, near Mt. Lassen]
      #3 [Uprooted tree, near Mt. Lassen]
      #4 [North-east slope, Mt. Lassen]
      #5 [Modoc lava beds]
      #6 [Aliso creek, south of Laguna Beach]
      #7 [Small cave in rocky terrain]
      #8 [Animal skull and wood fragment]
      #9 [Clear Lake bird refuge]
      #10 [Volcanic rock with vegetation]
    - Northern California ranches., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      #1 [Napa County]
      #2 [San Francisco - Sacramento highway near Fairfield]
      #3 [Colusa County]
    - Death Valley., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      #1 [Clouds over Panamint Range]
      #2 [Ruined building, Rhyolite, Nevada]
      #3 [Abandoned car]
      #4 [Desert buttes, behind 20 Mile Canyon]
      #5 [Road across Furnace Creek Wash]
      #6 [View from Zabriskie Point]
      #7 [Hills behind 20 Mile Canyon]
      #8 [Decaying structure]
      #9 [Red Rock Canyon Wall]
      #10 [Ampitheatre of the gods]
      #11 [Desert basin floor]
      #12 [Zabriskie Point]
      #13 [Mud wall with knoll]
      #14 [Salt flats on valley floor]
      #15 [Wind shapped rock]
      #16 Charcoal kilns, Panamints.
      #17 [Death Valley(?) snow covered mountains in background]
      #18 [Detail, wall above Golden canyon]
      #19 [Golden Canyon wall]
      #20 [Canyon wall]
    - Salton Sink, Death Valley., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      #1 [Mud(?) formation]
      #2 [Salton Sea]
      #3 [Badlands, edge of Borego Valley]
      #4 [Dead locotillo, Borego Valley]
      #5 [Palm frond fans, Borego Valley]
      #6 [Base of palm trees, Borego(?)]
      #7 [Palm trees, Borego Valley]
    - Yosemite Valley., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      #1 [Government Center under snow]
      #2 [Snow covered structure]
      #3 [Snow covered branches]
      #4 [Five snow covered trees]
      #5 [Two snow covered trees]
      #6 [Mountain peak with clouds]
      #7 [Snow covered mountain]
      #8 [Icicles]
      #9 [Snow covered trees across River Styx]
      #10 [Recently ploughed road]
      #11 [Ice on Iceburg Lake]
    - Red Rock Canyon., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      #1 [Rock ledge and cliffs, Red Rock Canyon]
      #2 [Triangular point, Red Rock Canyon]
      #3 [Joshua tree]
      #4 [Red ledge and cliffs, Red Rock Canyon]
      #5 Red Rock Canyon [base of sheer will]
      #6 Red Rock Canyon [base of wall with rubble]
      #7 Red Rock Canyon [detail, base of wall]
      #8 Red Rock Canyon [view, eroded canyon walls]
      #9 Red Rock Canyon [detail, base of wall in shape of pillars]
      #10 [Deeply eroded ridge, Red Rock Canyon]
      #11 Red Rock Canyon [detail, base of wall]
    - Monterey Bay Vicinity., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      #1 "Old Adobe," Carmel Valley, 1934.
      #2 [Ocean inlet with fishing boat and skiffs]
      #3 "Big Sur Ranch."
      #4 [Sand Dunes, Monterey Bay]
      #5 [Cormorants on rock formation]
      #6 [Salinas Valley ranch]
      #7 Uprooted cypress, Point Lobos.